Guide to the National Education Association-Commissions records, 1918-1982 NEA1002.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Commission on Professional Rights and Responsibilities, 1922-1981; Series 2; 82.75 Linear Feet
  - Workshop on PR&R-Materials [file 2/2], 1964-1968; Series 2 (Box 1001, Folder 6)
- Educational Policies Commission, 1936-1968; Series 3; 25 Linear Feet
  Educational Policies Commission was founded in December 1935, by joint action of the NEA and Department of Superintendence. It sought through cooperative means to develop for American education long-term policies which will merit support for the profession and all citizens.
  The commission sought to improve not only the theories about education but the also the conduct of education. It was made up of about 20 men and women and included the help of outside consultants.
  In 1968, the commission was dissolved by a vote of 16 members of the National Education Association and the American Association of School Administrators.
  Series contains materials created by the Educational Policies Commission. The files include materials from the civic education project and mental health project, correspondence, studies, manuscripts and publications, and meeting transcripts.
  These records provide excellent insight into the priorities and areas of interest of the EPC. The combination of meeting transcripts and studies, manuscripts, and reports, show how issues were raised, addressed, and how the commission responded to advance their beliefs about the future of education in the post WWII era.
  - Bacon, Francis Leonard, circa 1950; Series 3 (Box 1003, Folder 1)
    Contains 7 photos.
    Bacon, Francis Leonard
  - Civic Education Project-"Civic Education Handbook, Vol. I" by W. G. Carr [file 1/2], circa 1940; Series 3; Carr, William G. (Box 1003, Folder 2)
  - Civic Education Project-"Civic Education Handbook, Vol. I" by W. G. Carr [file 2/2], circa 1940; Series 3; Carr, William G. (Box 1003, Folder 3)
  - Civic Education Project-"Civic Education Handbook, Vol. II" by W. G. Carr [file 1/2], circa 1940; Series 3; Carr, William G. (Box 1003, Folder 4)
  - Civic Education Project-"Civic Education Handbook, Vol. II" by W. G. Carr [file 2/2], circa 1940; Series 3; Carr, William G. (Box 1003, Folder 5)
  - Civic Education Project-Correspondence, 1943-1967; Series 3 (Box 1003, Folder 6)
  - Civic Education Project-"Director's Report, Institute of National Government for Secondary School Students", March 1941; Series 3 (Box 1003, Folder 7)
  - Civic Education Project-"Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship", December 1940; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 1)
  - Civic Education Project-"Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship", February 1941; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 2)
  - Civic Education Project-"Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship", March 1941; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 3)
  - Civic Education Project-"Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship", April 1941; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 4)
  - Civic Education Project-"Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship", May 1941; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 5)
  - Civic Education Project-"Form Book No. 2, Regional Conferences" [file 1/4], October 1940-May 1951; Series 3 (Box 1004, Folder 6)
  - Civic Education Project-"Form Book No. 2, Regional Conferences" [file 2/4], October 1940-May 1951; Series 3 (Box 1005, Folder 1)
  - Civic Education Project-"Form Book No. 2, Regional Conferences" [file 3/4], October 1940-May 1951; Series 3 (Box 1005, Folder 2)
  - Civic Education Project-"Form Book No. 2, Regional Conferences" [file 4/4], October 1940-May 1951; Series 3 (Box 1005, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 1 [file 1/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1005, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 1 [file 2/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1005, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 1 [file 3/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1006, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 2 [file 1/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1006, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 2 [file 2/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1006, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (General Education Board) No. 2 [file 3/3], 1936-1944; Series 3 (Box 1006, Folder 4)
  - "Education of Free Men in American Democracy" Study Activities [file 1/2], October 1941-December 1941; Series 3 (Box 1006, Folder 5)
    Included "The Education of Free Men in American Democracy", by the Educational Policies Commission, 1941 (2 copies); and "The Education of Free Men in American Democracy (Study-Discussion Outline)", by the Educational Policies Commission, August 1941.
  - "Education of Free Men in American Democracy" Study Activities [file 2/2], October 1941-December 1941; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 1)
  - Freedom's Light: American Education Week Radio Program, 1936; Series 3 (Box 4048, Folder 11)
  - Ford Foundation [file 1/2], 1949-1957; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 2)
  - Ford Foundation [file 2/2], 1949-1957; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 3)
  - Lists of Members, 1941-1966; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 4)
  - Lists of Members Since 1936, March 1968; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 5)
  - Lists of Publications, 1942-1963; Series 3 (Box 1007, Folder 6)
  - List of Publications of the Educational Policies Commission, undated; series 3 (Box 4400, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts-"Communications Revolution and Education", July 1957; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts-"Mass Communications and Education", September 1957; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts-"Mass Communications and Education" (Plus Review), February 1958; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts-"The National Elementary Principal", February 1958; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 4)
  - Materials sent to Consultants and to Commission Members (1-10), February 1957-June 1957; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 5)
  - Materials sent to Consultants and to Commission Members (73-113), April 1944-November 1953; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 6)
  - Materials sent to Consultants and to Commission Members (114-120), February 1954-January 1956; Series 3 (Box 1008, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], May 1936; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], May 1936; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], May 1936; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], September 1937; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], September 1937; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts, April 1938; Series 3 (Box 1009, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 1938; Series 3 (Box 1010, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 1938; Series 3 (Box 1010, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts, May 7, 1939; Series 3 (Box 1010, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts, May 9, 1939; Series 3 (Box 1010, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts, November 1939; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 1)
    Contained "Educational Policies Commission, Ninth Meeting, May 1939, vols 1-8, Official Records".
  - Meeting Transcripts, November 21, 1939; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], September 1941; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], September 1941; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts, January 10, 1942; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts, February 19, 1942-February 20, 1942; Series 3 (Box 1011, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Transcripts, June 3, 1942; Series 3 (Box 1012, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts, June 5, 1942; Series 3 (Box 1012, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts, April 2, 1943; Series 3 (Box 1012, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts, March 11, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1012, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 11, 1944-March 14, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1012, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 11, 1944-March 14, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1013, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], September 27, 1944-September 29, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1013, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], September 27, 1944-September 29, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1013, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], September 27, 1944-September 29, 1944; Series 3 (Box 1013, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 27, 1945-March 29, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1014, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 27, 1945-March 29, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1014, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], September 15, 1945-September 17, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1014, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], September 15, 1945-September 17, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1014, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts, November 3, 1945-November 4, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1014, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], December 14, 1945-December 16, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1015, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], December 14, 1945-December 16, 1945; Series 3 (Box 1015, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], April 22, 1946-April 24, 1946; Series 3 (Box 1015, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], April 22, 1946-April 24, 1946; Series 3 (Box 1015, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], May 16, 1946-May 18, 1946; Series 3 (Box 1015, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], May 16, 1946-May 18, 1946; Series 3 (Box 1016, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts, December 12, 1946-December 14, 1946; Series 3 (Box 1016, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], May 4, 1947-May 7, 1947; Series 3 (Box 1016, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], May 4, 1947-May 7, 1947; Series 3 (Box 1016, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], May 4, 1947-May 7, 1947; Series 3 (Box 1016, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 4/4], May 4, 1947-May 7, 1947; Series 3 (Box 1017, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], September 24, 1948-September 25, 1948; Series 3 (Box 1017, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], September 24, 1948-September 25, 1948; Series 3 (Box 1017, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 11, 1949-March 12, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1017, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 11, 1949-March 12, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1017, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], October 6, 1949-October 8, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1018, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], October 6, 1949-October 8, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1018, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], October 6, 1949-October 8, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1018, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 4/4], October 6, 1949-October 8, 1949; Series 3 (Box 1018, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], March 30, 1950-April 1, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1018, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], March 30, 1950-April 1, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1019, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], March 30, 1950-April 1, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1019, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 4/4], March 30, 1950-April 1, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1019, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], October 5, 1950-October 7, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1019, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], October 5, 1950-October 7, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1019, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], October 5, 1950-October 7, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1020, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 4/4], October 5, 1950-October 7, 1950; Series 3 (Box 1020, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 1951; Series 3 (Box 1020, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 1951; Series 3 (Box 1020, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], October 4, 1951-October 6, 1951; Series 3 (Box 1020, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], October 4, 1951-October 6, 1951; Series 3 (Box 1021, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], October 4, 1951-October 6, 1951; Series 3 (Box 1021, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 4/4], October 4, 1951-October 6, 1951; Series 3 (Box 1021, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 1952; Series 3 (Box 1021, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 1952; Series 3 (Box 1021, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], October 1952; Series 3 (Box 1022, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], October 1952; Series 3 (Box 1022, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], October 1952; Series 3 (Box 1022, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 1953; Series 3 (Box 1022, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 1953; Series 3 (Box 1023, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], October 1, 1953-October 3, 1953; Series 3 (Box 1023, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/4], October 1, 1953-October 3, 1953; Series 3 (Box 1023, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/4], October 1, 1953-October 3, 1953; Series 3 (Box 1023, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/4], October 1, 1953-October 3, 1953; Series 3 (Box 1024, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], March 1954; Series 3 (Box 1024, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], March 1954; Series 3 (Box 1024, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], March 1954; Series 3 (Box 1024, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], September 1954; Series 3 (Box 1024, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], September 1954; Series 3 (Box 1025, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], April 1955; Series 3 (Box 1025, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], April 1955; Series 3 (Box 1025, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 1955; Series 3 (Box 1025, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 1955; Series 3 (Box 1026, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], April 1956; Series 3 (Box 1026, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], April 1956; Series 3 (Box 1026, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], April 1956; Series 3 (Box 1026, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], October 1956; Series 3 (Box 1026, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], October 1956; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], October 1956; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], April 1957; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], April 1957; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], April 1957; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], October 1957; Series 3 (Box 1027, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], October 1957; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], October 1957; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], December 1957; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], December 1957; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 1958; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 1958; Series 3 (Box 1028, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], October 1958; Series 3 (Box 1029, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], October 1958; Series 3 (Box 1029, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], April 1959; Series 3 (Box 1029, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], April 1959; Series 3 (Box 1029, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], October 1959; Series 3 (Box 1030, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], October 1959; Series 3 (Box 1030, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts, October 2, 1959-October 3, 1959; Series 3 (Box 1030, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts, October 16, 1959-October 17, 1959; Series 3 (Box 1030, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts, January 1960; Series 3 (Box 1031, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts, April 1960; Series 3 (Box 1031, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts, November 1960; Series 3 (Box 1031, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], January 1961; Series 3 (Box 1031, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], January 1961; Series 3 (Box 1031, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], April 1961; Series 3 (Box 1032, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], April 1961; Series 3 (Box 1032, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], April 1961; Series 3 (Box 1032, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts, November 1961; Series 3 (Box 1032, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], April 1962; Series 3 (Box 1033, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], April 1962; Series 3 (Box 1033, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 1962; Series 3 (Box 1033, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 1962; Series 3 (Box 1033, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts, April 4, 1963-April 6, 1963; Series 3 (Box 1033, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts (copy), April 4, 1963-April 6, 1963; Series 3 (Box 1034, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts, October 3, 1963; Series 3 (Box 1034, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts, October 4, 1963; Series 3 (Box 1034, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts, October 5, 1963; Series 3 (Box 1034, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/3], April 2, 1964-April 4, 1964; Series 3 (Box 1034, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/3], April 2, 1964-April 4, 1964; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 3/3], April 2, 1964-April 4, 1964; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], October 8, 1964-October 10, 1964; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], October 8, 1964-October 10, 1964; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 25, 1965-March 27, 1965; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 25, 1965-March 27, 1965; Series 3 (Box 1035, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 11, 1965-November 13, 1965; Series 3 (Box 1036, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 11, 1965-November 13, 1965; Series 3 (Box 1036, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], March 31, 1966-April 1, 1966; Series 3 (Box 1036, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], March 31, 1966-April 1, 1966; Series 3 (Box 1036, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 10, 1966-November 11, 1966; Series 3 (Box 1036, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 10, 1966-November 11, 1966; Series 3 (Box 1037, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], April 6, 1967-April 7, 1967; Series 3 (Box 1037, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], April 6, 1967-April 7, 1967; Series 3 (Box 1037, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 1/2], November 9, 1967-November 10, 1967; Series 3 (Box 1037, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Transcripts [file 2/2], November 9, 1967-November 10, 1967; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Transcripts, April 4, 1968; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 2)
  - Mental Health Project, 1956; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 3)
  - Mental Health Project-Cards with Contacts, circa 1955; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 4)
  - Mental Health Project-Copies of Exploration of Studies on Mental Health and Education, 1955-1956; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 5)
  - Mental Health Project-Correspondence, Reports [file 1/2], 1955-1956; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 6)
  - Mental Health Project-Correspondence, Reports [file 2/2], 1955-1956; Series 3 (Box 1038, Folder 7)
  - Mental Health Project-Replies and Non-Replies, 1955-1956; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Steering Committee Meetings, 1956; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936-1954; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 3)
  - "Moral and Spiritual Values for your Children" (in Spanish), circa 1950; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 4)
  - NEA510 R 36-43; Our American Schools, Does Education Pay, Teacher Meeting by Radio, The Neglected Weapon, 1936-1943; NEA1002.RG (Box 2809, Folder 1)
  - Original and Supplementary Grants and Material Relating to the Future of the Commission, 1941; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets, 1955; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 6)
  - Papers-Adult Education, 1948-1954; Series 3 (Box 1039, Folder 7)
  - Papers-Area C Meetings [file 1/2], 1954; Series 3 (Box 1040, Folder 1)
  - Papers-Area C Meetings [file 2/2], 1954; Series 3 (Box 1040, Folder 2)
  - Papers-"Educational Policies Commissions, Present and Proposed", 1942; Series 3 (Box 1040, Folder 3)
  - Papers-Higher Education, 1954-1957; Series 3 (Box 1040, Folder 4)
  - Papers-State and Private Education, 1951-1952; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1958; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 2)
    Contains 19 photos and 249 negatives.
  - Photographs, January 1959; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 3)
    Contains 2 photos.
  - Photographs, October 1959; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 4)
    Contains 3 photos and 7 negatives.
  - Photographs-Members, 1949-1958; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 5)
    Contains 17 photos and 1 negative.
  - Proceedings of Conferences, Educating Youth for the Responsibilities of Citizenship, 1940-1941; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 6)
  - Projects-Correspondence about Public Education and the Future of America, 1955; Series 3 (Box 1042, Folder 7)
  - Projects-Mass Communications [file 1/4], 1956-1958; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 1)
  - Projects-Mass Communications [file 2/4], 1956-1958; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 2)
  - Projects-Mass Communications [file 3/4], 1956-1958; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 3)
  - Projects-Mass Communications [file 4/4], 1956-1958; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 4)
  - Projects-Mass Communications-Vote by Mail, 1958; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 5)
  - Projects-Professional Organizations in American Education [file 1/2], 1956-1957; Series 3 (Box 1043, Folder 6)
    Contains 1 dry mount.
  - Projects-Professional Organizations in American Education [file 2/2], 1956-1957; Series 3 (Box 1044, Folder 1)
  - Projects-Public Education and the Future of America, 1954-1955; Series 3 (Box 1044, Folder 2)
  - Publications List, 1957; series 3 (Box 4383, Folder 3)
  - Recommended Schools for "Education for all American Children", circa 1945; Series 3 (Box 1044, Folder 3)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. I [file 1/3], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1044, Folder 4)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. I [file 2/3], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1044, Folder 5)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. I [file 3/3], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1045, Folder 1)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. II [file 1/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1045, Folder 2)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. II [file 2/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1045, Folder 3)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. II [file 3/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1045, Folder 4)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. II [file 4/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1046, Folder 1)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. III [file 1/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1046, Folder 2)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. III [file 2/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1046, Folder 3)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. III [file 3/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1046, Folder 4)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. III [file 4/4], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1046, Folder 5)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. IV [file 1/2], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1047, Folder 1)
  - Record of Proposals, Plans and Correspondence for "Education for all American Children", Vol. IV [file 2/2], 1945-1947; Series 3 (Box 1047, Folder 2)